siriuscanada.ca 2019-05-07

# Privacy Policy | SiriusXM Canada

If you are a new SiriusXM Canada subscriber on or after September 1, 2015, or if you use the Site on and after this date, this Privacy Policy applies to you.

If you are a **Sirius Canada subscriber** prior to September 1, 2015, the Privacy Policy applicable to your subscription can be found here: <https://www.siriusxm.ca/privacy-policy-sirius/>

If you are an **XM Canada subscriber** prior to September 1, 2015, the Privacy Policy applicable to your subscription can be found here: <https://www.siriusxm.ca/privacy-policy-xm/>

We have updated our Privacy Policy to make it more modern and easy to understand, and to bring Sirius and XM customers under a single uniform privacy policy. This update is primarily meant to bring our customers under one privacy policy, regardless of the SiriusXM Canada services you use. In addition, we have modernized our disclosure policy by outlining our use of social media, mobile, and online analytics information. We also describe in more detail how we collect and receive personal information from third parties.

**Last Updated: September 1, 2015**

Your privacy is important to Sirius XM Canada Inc. (referred to as **“SiriusXM”** , **“we”** or **“us”** in this Privacy Policy). This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, receive, store, use and disclose your personal information. When you use siriusxm.ca (the **“Site”** ), when you sign up for and use our satellite radio service, when you purchase a satellite radio or a vehicle that includes a satellite radio, when you use SiriusXM Internet Radio through our mobile and browser-based apps and players, and all related sites, players, widgets, tools, apps, data, software, APIs and other services provided by SiriusXM (the **“Services”** ), you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and we cannot tailor our use of your personal information to your satisfaction, please do not use this Site or purchase, order, or use our Services.

We are responsible for the personal information under our control and we have designated a Privacy Officer who is responsible for our compliance with this Privacy Policy and with privacy legislation.

Personal information may be stored in Canada or with our affiliates and service providers in foreign countries, including in the United States, where it will be subject to the legal regimes of those jurisdictions.

The following is a _summary_ of how we collect, use, and share personal information. For a full description of our practices relating to personal information please read this Policy in its entirety.

#### Information we collect

We collect information when you:

  * purchase and subscribe to our Services or sign up for a trial to our Services
  * purchase a satellite radio, including satellite radios integrated into vehicles
  * create an account to use our Site and our Services
  * use our Site and our Internet-delivered Services
  * contact us for support or customer service
  * use a SiriusXM page on a social media service, such as our Facebook and Google+ pages or our YouTube channel
  * sign up for our newsletter
  * enter SiriusXM contests or promotions
  * contact us for musical requests or to comment on one of our shows on-air.

We also receive personal information from automakers, retail partners, and other third party information providers.

#### How we use you the personal information we collect and receive

We use personal information to operate the Sites and Services, for our marketing purposes, and to comply with legal requirements. You may opt out of uses of your personal information that are not required for us to provide the Site and Services. You may not opt-out of any use or disclosure of your personal information that is required for us to provide the Site and Services without also discontinuing your use of the Site or Services.

#### Information that we share

We share your information with service providers that assist us in delivering our Services, with information processors to help us communicate with and better understand our subscribers, and with marketing partners such as automakers, who market SiriusXM Canada services on our behalf. These third parties have access to your personal information only to the extent necessary to perform the functions they carry out on our behalf, are not permitted to use it for other purposes, and are bound to keep the information strictly confidential. You may opt-out from our communications related to the marketing of our Services without any impact on your use of the Site or Services.

We also may disclose your information when permitted or required to by law, to enforce our [Customer Agreement](https://www.siriusxm.ca/terms-and-conditions/) and our legal relationships with third parties, and to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues.

## 1\. Information we collect

We collect information when you:

  * purchase and subscribe to our Services or sign up for a trial to our Services
  * purchase a satellite radio, including satellite radios integrated into vehicles
  * use our Site and our Services
  * create an account to use our Site and our Services
  * contact us for support or customer service
  * use a SiriusXM page on a social media service, such as our Facebook and Google+ pages or our YouTube channel
  * sign up for our newsletter
  * enter SiriusXM contests or promotions
  * contact us for musical requests or to comment on one of our shows on-air.

#### a. Information you give us

When you sign up to subscribe to our Services, sign up for trials of our Services, contact us for support or information, order items from the store on our Site, sign up for a newsletter or other marketing communications, or sign up for a contest or promotion, we may collect:

  * your name, address, telephone number, and e­mail address
  * your payment information such are your credit card number and associated information
  * your satellite radio’s Radio ID or Electronic Serial Number ( **“ESN”** )
  * demographic information, including language of preference, referral source, and other marketing information if you agree to provide it.

You may also give us personal information when you use the interactive portions of our Site and Services. Note that any information you post on interactive Sites and Services are often public and can be seen by others. Finally, we may also collect information you give us when we interact with you on social services such as Facebook, Google+, and Twitter.

#### b. Information we collect automatically from the use of our Site and Services

Our Site and our Services collect the following information:

**Cookies:** When you view our Site, we may store small text files on your device called cookies to automatically recognize you each time you visit. Cookies can help us in many ways, for example, by allowing us to tailor the Site to better match your interests or to save your password so that you do not have to re-enter it each time. Cookies also are used to help us track visitors, track usage, conduct research, target advertising, and improve our content and Services. Other sites may also use our cookie to anonymously identify your browser when you visit, such as advertising services that may appear on other sites.

We may also allow our business partners to use cookies on the Site and Services for the purposes listed above, including Google Analytics cookies to track activity related to our Site and Services, to conduct research, and to display relevant advertising on other sites. You can opt-out of Google Analytics by installing the utility available at the following link:

<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>

You may choose not to be recognized through cookies by adjusting your browser settings. Please refer to your browser to erase cookies from your device, block all cookies, block certain types of cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored on your device. If you prevent a cookie from being sent and stored on your device, you may limit the functionality of the Site and Services.

**Server Logs:** When you use our Site and our SiriusXM Internet Radio service, we may also automatically collect and store certain information in server logs. This may include:

  * domain name of the website from which you came, number of visits, average time spent on the Site, and the pages you viewed
  * details of how you used our Services, such as which channels and shows you listened to, and when and how long you listened to them
  * device information such as your unique device identifier, device type, web-browser type and version, operating system version, and the version of the SiriusXM Internet Radio application being used
  * Internet protocol address

**Location information:  **The Site and SiriusXM Internet Radio service will determine your location for the purposes of controlling access to certain content using your Internet protocol address, and if you are using the SiriusXM Internet Radio mobile applications, GPS signals.

#### c. Information we receive from other sources

_i. Automaker and retail partners_

We may receive personal information from our automaker, dealer, and retail partners who distribute and sell SiriusXM satellite radios. When you purchase a SiriusXM satellite radio (either as a stand-alone device or integrated into a vehicle), our partners will often ask for your consent to collect your information and to share it with certain third-parties, including SiriusXM. Where our partners have sought such consent, we may receive your name, address, telephone number, your satellite radio’s Radio ID or ESN, and vehicle’s VIN, make, model, and whether you purchased or leased the vehicle. In certain instances we may also receive your email address and demographic information. We also obtain information from resellers of vehicles which include a SiriusXM satellite radio.

_ii. Social media services_

The collection and use of your personal information when using a social media service such as Facebook, Google+, or Twitter is guided by the service’s privacy policy and your privacy settings on the service. We may receive information from social media services in accordance with their privacy policies and your privacy settings on those services. Note that any comments that you post on our Facebook and Google+ and our other social media pages are public and can be seen by others.

_iii. Marketing service providers_

We may supplement the information you provide to us by acquiring commercially available demographic and marketing information from third parties. Most often this information relates to any recent vehicle purchase made by potential subscribers.

These third party companies must follow privacy laws when collecting and sharing the information with SiriusXM. We will only use information provided by third parties in accordance with the consent they represent to us they have obtained.

## 2\. How we use the personal information we collect and receive

#### a. To operate the Site and the Services

We use the personal information we collect and receive to provide you with the Services, improve the Services, develop new Services, personalize our Services, to send you Service-related communications, improve and refine our content offerings, to activate satellite radios and SiriusXM Internet Radio accounts, provide login credentials to the Site and Services, to analyze our subscriber base for marketing purposes, and for billing the Services.

We may use your information to determine your creditworthiness as well as for fraud protection.

We use your information to improve and personalize the Site. We will you use your information to provide you with login sessions on the Site and to remember that you are logged it. Other websites may use the cookie we leave on your device in order to provide you with more relevant advertising, including advertising that we purchase. You can disable cookies and limit their use by adjusting the settings of your browser.

We may use your listening history information to account for our use of licensed content. This information will be aggregated and supplied to content licensors in way that renders the information anonymous.

When using our online store on the Site, we will use your information to fulfill orders and deliver your purchases

#### b. For our marketing purposes

We use your information to contact you to offer extensions of Service, new products or Services, to send information on special offers, promotions, or information which we think may interest you, and to perform market research. We aggregate, compare, analyze, and process the personal information we collect and receive for marketing purposes. We use your personal information and obtain marketing assistance and processing to better understand our subscribers and to better reach our subscribers, whether through direct communication or advertising.

With your consent, we will use your information to provide you with offers from third party partners which we believe may be of interest to you. For example, we may offer opportunities or information from content providers, such as from musical artists, sports, news, and talk programming providers. We may also send information on products, services, or opportunities from automakers or retailers of satellite radios or other third party partners.

You may choose to not participate in direct marketing communications of products and services from SiriusXM or any of our marketing partners.

To opt out of the receipt of direct marketing communications please email [care@siriusxm.ca](mailto:care@siriusxm.ca) or call **1-888-539-7474**.

#### c. To comply with legal requirements

We may use your information to enforce our Customer Agreement, any other applicable terms and conditions and other agreements to which SiriusXM is bound, and to protect the rights and property of SiriusXM and our partners. When using the SiriusXM Internet Radio service, we use anonymized location information to enforce content restrictions.

**We will ask for your consent before using information for a purpose other than those that are set out in this Privacy Policy.**

## 3\. Information that we share

We share your information with service providers that assist us in delivering our Services, with information processors to help us communicate with and better understand our subscribers, and with marketing partners such as automakers, who market SiriusXM Canada services on our behalf. These third parties have access to your personal information only to the extent necessary to perform the functions they carry out on our behalf, are not permitted to use it for other purposes, and are bound to keep the information strictly confidential. We will also share your information when required or compelled to by law.

#### a. With service providers

We share your personal information with service providers who we use to deliver the Services and service providers who help us optimize and market our Services. For example we have partnered with other companies to provide infrastructure and IT services, personalize and optimize our Site and Services, process credit card transactions, provide customer service, fulfill orders, administer rebates and promotional offers, collect debts, analyze and enhance data, and process consumer surveys.

#### b. With external processors and marketing service providers

We share your information with trusted third parties to analyze personal information for us, including in order to better understand our subscribers, to improve our marketing, and to communicate more effectively with you.

#### c. With marketing partners

On occasion we will share information with third party marketers. For example, we may share information with our automaker partners to help them maintain up to date ownership information on the vehicles they sell and lease. We may also share information with third parties in order to provide you with offers and promotions we feel may be of value to you. You may withdraw your consent for such information sharing without any impact on your Services.

#### d. With professional services providers

We may share your information where necessary with our professional service providers such as our external lawyers, accountants, and other professional services advisers.

#### e. Non-identifying information

We may share aggregated information that does not identify you personally with the public or our partners. For example, we may share aggregated statistical information publicly to show trends about the general use of our Site and Services.

#### f. Legal disclosures

We will share personal information with companies, organizations or individuals if we have a good faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of the information is reasonably necessary to:

  * meet any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request
  * enforce our Customer Agreement and our legal relationships with third parties, including investigation of potential violations
  * detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues

#### g. Business Transfers

If SiriusXM is involved in a merger, acquisition or asset sale, we may share aggregated information with potential purchasers on a confidential basis solely to allow them to assess the business opportunity. In the event such a transaction is completed, we will continue to ensure the confidentiality of any personal information and give you notice before your personal information is transferred to an acquirer.

## 4\. Transparency and choice

#### a. Information and uses that we require to provide you with Services

You may not opt-out of any use or disclosure of your personal information that is required for us to provide the Site and Services without also discontinuing your use of the Site or Services.

#### b. Information uses from which you can opt-out on request

You may opt out of the following disclosures and uses of your personal information without impact on your use of our Services. You may do so by emailing [privacy@siriusxm.ca](mailto:privacy@siriusxm.ca).

_i. Marketing communication_

You may opt-out from our communications related to the marketing of our Services without any impact on your use of the Site or Services.

_ii. Partner and joint marketing uses_

You may opt out of any disclosure to third party marketers without any impact on your use of the Site or the Services.

#### c. Access and update your information

We give you access to a broad range of information about your account and your interactions with us in the **“My Account”** portion of the Site. You may also have access to the foregoing by contacting customer care by phone or email. You are responsible for updating and maintaining the truth and accuracy of the personal information you provide to us.

#### d. Information security

To help protect the confidentiality of personal information, we use administrative and technological safeguards appropriate to the sensitivity of the personal information being protected. For instance, we operate secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection systems. Personal information is stored in secured locations and on services located either at our offices or at the facilities of our data storage providers and technology service providers.

We protect the security of the information you provide to make purchases and to activate subscriptions online by using Secure Sockets Layer software, which encrypts the transmission of such information to our Services.

## 5\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

SiriusXM reserves the right to modify or supplement this Privacy Policy statement at anytime. If we make any material change to this Privacy Policy, we will update this Site to include such changes and post a notice on our home page with a link to the updated Privacy Policy. Please read any such notice and the new Privacy Policy statement. Your continued use of this Site and the Services after we post such notice will constitute your acceptance of the new terms and their application to your use of the Site and the Services. Information disclosed for such use, including information previously furnished to us, will be treated as if any changes to this Privacy Policy formed the initial terms. However, we will seek your consent if we want to use your personal information for purposes other than those you have agreed to previously.

## 6\. Jurisdiction

SiriusXM is a federally regulated entity in Canada. We only make our Services available to persons located in Canada. As a result, this privacy Privacy Policy is intended to comply and should be interpreted in accordance with the federal privacy laws of Canada.

#### Contact Us

If you wish to contact our Privacy Officer, you can do one of the following:

By Email [privacy@siriusxm.ca](mailto:privacy@siriusxm.ca); or,

By Mail Attn: Privacy Officer, Sirius XM Canada Inc., 135 Liberty Street, Suite 400, M6K 1A7

## Select Your Service

The website is customized to show channels and plans for the  Service.

Sirius XM SiriusXM

Don't know what service you have? Try our VIN lookup tool | I want to explore

Don't know what service you have? Use our VIN lookup tool.  
Don’t have a radio? Try [SiriusXM streaming](https://player.siriusxm.ca/).
